hi everybody this is crystal so today
i'm going to show you how to make this
very quick
pretty quick and easy uh blanket you can
make it a baby blanket size you can make
it throw size you can make it full size
king size whatever you want um
and it's very it's like i said it's very
easy as long as you know the basic
stitches you'll be able to do it
and i will give you the measurement of
mine and show you how much yarn i used
um just to give you an idea
so my measures mine's folded in half
because the tables are not that big mine
measures
about 32 inches
one way
and about
close to 40 inches
the other so this is what this stitch
looks like
just very easy
it makes it like tiny
[Music]
little proof subs i guess anyways let's
go ahead and get started and i'll show
you the yarn that i used
okay for this project uh i'm going to be
using
caron babycakes so this is a medium
weight
number four 100 acrylic yarn
um no which i'm sorry 82 acrylic uh
18 nylon medium weight number four you
do not have to use this yarn
um you don't even have to use a medium
weight number four because i'll give you
your chain multiple and you can chain
for as big as you want your blanket to
be but
this is what i use the color i have in
my hand it's called
lavender and there are 560 yards per
cake and i
went through two entire cakes for the
size of blanket that i
made so that
and then i'm gonna be using a size j
which is a six millimeter
crochet hook okay so this like i
mentioned it is a very
uh beginner friendly project and
it has a one it's just a one row repeat
so the multiple
for this stitch in case you want to make
yours bigger or smaller you're using a
bigger different yarn or you want to use
this stitch for something else it is a
multiple
of three so which your uh beginning
chain needs to be evenly divisible by
three
i'm going to show you on a smaller scale
but for my blanket i chained 123
stitches so if you're following along
with me and once you get your 123
stitches
uh made you want to put two double
crochets
in the third stitch from the hook so we
don't count the one that's on our hook
and we count one
two three so in that third stitch
you want to put two double crochets into
it
there's one and
there is two like that
and then we're going to skip two
stitches and then we're going to work in
the neck so we skip skip
now we're going to start the repeat of
row one and we're going to make a shell
into the next stitch now the shell is
very easy to make
so we skip our two and in the next
stitch we're going to put
one single crochet
[Music]
and two double crochets into the same
stitch so that's the shell for this
pattern one
single and two doubles into the same
stitch is
what i'm calling a shell for this
pattern
now we're going to repeat that until we
get to the end of the row
so we're going to skip two stitches skip
skip
and we're going to put a shell into the
next so skip two and then next we're
gonna put
one single crochet and
two double crochets there's one
and there's two so that's the shell
again
skip two stitches skip skip and in the
next stitch
we're going to put one single crochet
and two doubles so that's the the shell
all into the same stitch we're going to
repeat this pattern
until we get to the end of the row skip
two
skip skip and in the next we make the
shell which is
one single and
two doubles one
and two so go ahead and repeat this
pattern
all the way until you get to the end and
i'll meet back up with you at the end of
the row
okay i've made it to the end i just did
a shell and i have three stitches that
remain
i want to skip two stitches and put a
single crochet
into the last stitch
and that will end row one and you should
have a total if you're following along
with me
of 40 shells here 40 of the shells
so now we're gonna start row two and row
two is actually the repeat row for the
entire
blanket so it's like i said it's very
very easy so we are going to chain
two and turn our work
and we're gonna put two double crochets
right back into that same stitch so that
single crochet from the previous row
we're gonna work two double crochets
into that spot
so there's one and there's two
and now we're going to skip two stitches
and we're going to work a shell into the
next so if we skip two stitches
skip skip the next stitch is going to be
the single crochet of the shell from the
previous row
so we're going to work a shell into that
stitch so we're going to go into that
single crochet there
and work a single crochet and
two doubles that's the shell
into that same stitch like that
and then we're going to repeat that
until we get to the end of the row
so we're going to skip two stitches so
we're skipping the two doubles
of the previous shell and then that
single crochet of the previous shell
we're going to work a shell so we're
going to work one single
and two doubles into that same stitch
and again repeat skip two stitches skip
skip and in the next which is the single
crochet from the previous row we work a
shell
so single crochet and two doubles into
that same stitch
and we're going to repeat this until we
get to the end
of our row
so i'll show you one more time we skip
two skip
skip and then we'll be where the single
crochet is from the previous row
and in that single crochet we make a
shell so we single crochet into it
and put two double crochets into it one
and two so continue this until you get
to the end
all right when you make it i just did my
last shell and
i have three stitches here that remain
i want to skip two stitches
and i want to put a single crochet into
the last
stitch
just like that again you'll have 40
shells at the end of row two
and row two is the repeat row so we're
just going to keep repeating
that row so let's do it again so for row
three i'm just going to repeat row two
so i'm going to do a chain of two and
turn my work
and then i'm going to put two double
crochets right back into that
very first stitch there that single
crochet from the previous row
go ahead and work two doubles in it
like that and then we skip two skip
skip and in the next stitch which is the
single crochet from the previous row
we work a shell so we're going to work a
single crochet
and two doubles into that same spot
again skip two stitches skip
skip and in the next stitch which is a
single crochet from the previous row
we're going to work a shell so we're
going to go into it and
single crochet and two doubles
into the same stitch so i'm just
repeating what i did
on row two until i get to the end of the
row
and when you make it to the end here i
just did my last shell
and you're you're at your last three
stitches you want to go ahead and single
crochet into this
last stitch here it's actually that
chain
two that we started with to single
crochet into the top of it
there we go 40 shells still if you're
following along with me
that's it we're just going to keep
repeating row two and you repeat it
until you get your blanket as a long
or as tall or as wide as you want it to
be
this uh pattern can be worked either way
the shells look good running this way
or even this way it looks good both ways
okay like i said i went ahead and i
worked until i reached about 32 inches
um you can make it longer of course
wider like i said just in multiples of
three for your beginning chain
and that's it now if you want i actually
just did until i ran out of two of my
counter kicks and then
it made it about 32 inches tall
and if you want to make it um i put a
border on it
i'm not gonna put a border on it i think
it looks fine without one kind of just
like a simple
really simple blanket no border no
anything
but if you did want to put a border
maybe a simple single crochet border
with the same color or maybe you know
what
anything you really want you know like i
i really prefer
mine i think this blanket being such a
simple pattern
and it has quite a bit of texture even
though it's so simple
i'm going to leave it simple and i'm not
going to border it all by by but
by all means you can add a border single
crochet border you can add a picot
border you can add a shell border
you know whatever you want to do if
you're a beginner i would you know you
can leave it just plain like i
am it makes great gift for somebody
whether it be a large blanket
or a baby blanket so i hope you enjoyed
my tutorial and i hope you were able to
follow along
um don't forget to give this video a
like thumbs up
don't forget to subscribe and check out
all my other tutorials i have hundreds
and hundreds
of them if you make this or anything
crochet or knitted it doesn't even have
to be my design i'd rather see a picture
of it you can come follow me on
instagram
hashtag me at bago d crochet and i like
to check out people's work
even if it's not my designs i still like
to look
and you can um show me any yarn holes
i really like that stuff so that's it
everybody
thanks for watching have a good day